The fast and the furriest.
Monkey Up is a comedy, family film directed by Robert Vince.
A talking monkey seeks to gain fame and fortune as a movie star,
but instead finds what's most important, a family.
Mr. Hartz, played by John Ratzenberger.
Angelino Cappello, played by Danny Woodburn.
Monty (voice), played by Skylar Astin.
Ethan Andrews, played by Caleb Burgess.
Desmond, played by David Milchard.
Sophie Andrews, played by Kayden Magnuson.
Monkey Man is a 2024 action thriller film directed and produced by Dev Patel in his directorial
debut, who also co-wrote the screenplay with Paul Angunawela and John Collee.
The film stars Patel as Kid, a man who seeks vengeance on the
corrupt leaders responsible for his mother's death.
Sharlto Copley, Pitobash, and Vipin Sharma are featured in supporting roles.
Monkey Man premiered at South by Southwest on March 11, 2024, and was released
theatrically in the United States and Canada by Universal Pictures on April 5, 2024.
The film was critically acclaimed and grossed $35 million
worldwide against a $10 million budget.
It was nominated at the 78th BAFTA Awards for Outstanding
Debut by a British Writer, Director or Producer.
The tone is lighthearted.